HIGUERA HAROL

Mobile Developer

192-0354, Tokyo-to Hachioji-shi Matsugaya 17 banchi 1-811

Mobile: 808-3852-2801

Email: harolhiguera2005@gmail.com

OVERVIEW

Experienced mobile developer, a quick and enthusiastic learner with a solid theoretical and practical academic background in Electronic Engineering, software and maths, over 7 years of experience on Android development, IOS development, and recently on cross-platform development with Flutter technologies.

CORE STRENGTHS

- · Creative
- · Tidy and organized
- Logic thinking
- Very helpful
- · Theoretical and practical engineering
- Open minded to explore multidisciplinary fields of engineering
- Fast learner
- · Good attention to detail and design
- Deadline-oriented
- Committed
- · Strong problem solving skills
- Honest and punctual

❖ INDUSTRY KNOLEDGE

- Android Development.
- IOS development.
- Flutter
- Back-end applications architecture and development (Java).

***** TECHNICAL SKILLS

STRONG PROGRAMING SKILLS:

- Swift
- Kotlin
- Flutter
- Java

OTHER PROGRAMING SKILLS:

- SQL
- Objective C.
- C
- MATLAB
- PHP
- Java Script

MOBILE DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE:

- Git
- CircleCl configurations.
- Jira, Trello, Gantt Chart, Scrum,
- Firebase products integration.
- Geo-location features.
- Deployment of mobile applications
- UI concept design.
- High integration of WebViews.
- Realm, SQL, Core-Data.
- Favourite Architecture: MVVM
- Development, testing and distribution.

IOS DEVELOPMENT:

- **Experience**: 5 years.
- Languages: Swift, Objective C.
- Architectures: MVVM, Singleton.
- Responsive performance according to design requirements for multiple devices.
- In-app purchases.
- Automatic distribution with CircleCl, Fastlane and Firebase Distribution.
- Development, testing and distribution.
- Recent libraries and development tools: Moya, RealmSwift, Firebase.

DEVELOPMENT WITH FLUTTER:

- **Experience**: 0.5 years
- Languages: Dart
- Tools: Android Studio, Visual Studio Code
- Provider design pattern.
- Responsive performance according to design requirements for iOS and Android platforms.
- Automatic distribution with CircleCI, Fastlane, and Firebase Distribution.
- In-app purchases.
- Connection to Restful API and GraphQL based services.

ANDROID DEVELOPMENT:

- Experience: 7 years.
- Languages: Java, Kotlin.
- Responsive IUs for multiple screen sizes and screen densities.
- Android design patterns: MVVM with Dagger2, JetPack and RxJava.
- Experience with Bluetooth connectivity.
- Recent libraries and development tools: Retrofit, Dagger 2, RxJava, RxAndroid, Picasso, Glide, Butterknife, LeakCanary, Espresso, Mockito.

SERVER APPLICATIONS:

- **Experience**: 1.5 years
- Languages: Java, SQL
- Java/JEE applications (Spring Boot, JPA, Hibernate)
- Tools: Eclipse, Oracle Data Modeler, PGAdmin 4, Postman, ngrok, Gradle.
- Databases: Postgres, Firebase Cloud Firestore
- MVC design pattern
- Server application architecture for a mobile application service.
- Restful API
- Interaction with third parties such as Firebase and Stripe for payments purposes.
- Unit Testing.
- API documentation
- Clean code
- AWS deployment and multiple configurations.
- Experience with Blockchain based systems and Cryptocurrencies.

EXPERIENCE

Mobile Application developer Monstar Lab, Inc, **Tokyo**, **Japan**

10/2018 to present

https://monstar-lab.com/

DUTIES:

Depending on the project I am assigned to:

- Make part of development process with other engineers, mobile and backend, also project managers and designers.
- Design the architecture of applications to be developed from scratch.
- Code review.

- Add new functionalities to existing applications.
- Lead iOS development team. Maximum 4 people so far.
- Deployment of IOS and Android applications to the app store and play store.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS:

- So far by working in this company I have acquired a great experience in dealing with important clients in Japan.
- Great experience in working with Agile Methodologies and thigh deadlines.
- Improved my skills particularly working with RxSwift for iOS.
- Learned Flutter development by working on real projects.
- Improved my communication skills in the Japanese Language.

RELEVANT PROJECTS:

RHYTHMMEAL APP

Description: A game type of application that challenges users to create music based on entering predefined combinations and mix it up with the catchy background tracks. The app has a concept of Cooking sounds to make a great meal. It contains various animations and sounds processing. It was developed with Flutter by two mobile engineers.

Role: Flutter Developer. **Languages**: Dart.

Country of release: Japan. Release Date: August 2020.

MISUMI APP

Description: Hybrid IOS application of the kind of marketplace for MISUMI Group Inc. Particularly, this application had lots of WebView integrations. It was developed along with the Android version. The iOS development team was formed of 4 people.

Role: IOS Developer. Languages: Swift.

Country of release: Korea, Vietnam and Thailand.

Store: https://apps.apple.com/jp/app/misumi-e-catalog-vietnam/id1446374599

DOSHITERU APP

Description: iOS and Android application that displays people's status in their homes. It was developed for Hitachi and aimed to keep close contact with the elders by displaying movement data taken from sensors installed in their homes. These apps were developed by three people where I was the leader on both sides.

Role: Mobile application developer leader.

Languages: Java, Swift. Country of release: Japan.

URL: https://kadenfan.hitachi.co.jp/doshiteru/

NISSAN CATALOG APP

Description: iOS Application that displays the latest catalogue of cars sold by Nissan Motors. Its content is updated from a server-side. It was developed for lpads. The job consisted in add new features and make it suitable for the current lpad screen models.

Role: IOS Developer. Languages: Objective C.

Country of release: Korea, Vietnam and Thailand.

Store:https://apps.apple.com/jp/app/%E6%97%A5%E7%94%A3%E3%82%AB%E3%82%BF%E3%83%AD% E3%82%B0/id519595255

Mobile Application Architect and developer Beepnow, **Osaka**, **Japan**

04/2017 to 09/2018

DEVELOPMENT TEAM: 1 member

DUTIES:

- Design of total mobile application and back-end services according to requirements.
- Development of back-end services.
- Development of IOS mobile application.
- Testina.
- Deployment of back-end applications in Amazon web services.
- Deployment of IOS application to apple store.
- Creation of Restful API documentation for mobile applications and Admin Portal.
- Work in cooperation with Malaysian company in charge of creating crypto wallet service for payments.
- Travel abroad in order to attend events related to the business.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS:

- Dramatically increased experience in architecture design of complex mobile application solutions and development with Spring Boot framework.
- In cooperation with the Malaysian company BTM, we achieved the design of a solution for payments and transactions for the business model involving a cryptocurrency.

PROJECTS:

BEEPNOW APP

Description: A mobile application that connects "service seekers" and "service providers" together, allowing people to earn income on a freelance basis.

Role: IOS single Developer. Designer (Illustrator, Photoshop)

Languages: Swift.

Country of releasing: Japan.

Features: User location, Consumes restful based API services, Push notifications, login with Facebook and Line SDKs, mobile number verification, chat implementation using Firebase-firestore DB. Escrow business model implementation.

BEEPNOW BACK-END SERVICES

Description: Java/JEE application service for beepnow app.

Role: Application architect, back-end developer.

Languages: Java, SQL.

Features: Spring boot based application, MVC design pattern, Oauth2, Postgres DB, Strong integration with Stripe API for marketplace kind of business logic, Firebase integration for authentication and storage purposes, Usage of Sengrid services, AWS S3 storage. Spring Restdocs Asciidoctor for documentation purposes.

Mobile Developer Launchpad D Pty Ltd, **Sydney, Australia**

10/2015 to 04/2017

https://launchpadd.com.au/

DEVELOPMENT TEAM: 10 members

DUTIES:

- Responsible for developing mobile applications totally or in cooperation with other developers.
- Developer for Android and IOS platforms.
- Agile development, daily scrum.
- Development under deadline and estimation
- Testing.
- Occasionally cooperate with Spring boot backend application development.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS:

- Acquired lots of expertise and knowledge on mobile development in general and best practices.
- Increased development speed mainly to develop in Android Java and Swift.
- Become the best Android developer in the team, for better architecture solutions and better performance.

PROJECTS:

HUSKEE

Description: Huskee Swap is an idea that enables people to eliminate disposable cups while borrowing sustainable well-made cups. HuskeeSwap application provides a mechanism to find cups in the cafes nearby, in order to borrow or return the cups. Made for iOS and Android.

Role: Android single developer.

Languages: Kotlin. Duration: 6 months.

Country of releasing: Australia, Uk, US.

Features: User location, Credit card payments. Consumes Restful API. Developed with RxJava, Dagger2

and Jetpack. MVVM architecture pattern. System integrated with Stripe Connect.

URL: https://huskee.co/

BLINK

Description: A mobile application that allows finding deals and discounts on bars and venues nearby. Also, allows individuals to check in venues so people could know the attendance and where is the fun taken place. The entire system consists of server application, content management system and mobile applications for Android and IOS platforms.

Role: Android developer. Languages: Java. Duration: 7 months.

Country of releasing: New Zealand.

Features: User location, Consumes Restful API, Image gallery, Push notifications using GCM, Facebook SDK.

URL: http://www.blinkentertainment.com.au/

IFISHCOMPS

Description: Mobile application to publish and discover galleries, catches and information about fishing events and competitions.

Role: Android single developer, IOS developer, back-end programmer.

Languages: Java, Objective C, php.

Duration: 3 months.

Country of releasing: Australia.

Features: Interaction with remote server, Image and video galleries, PayPal payment integration, App

featured for users and administrator. **URL:** http://www.ifishcomps.com/

PUG CHALK

Description: An application made for pug's lovers who want to share customized pictures of their pugs by adding, and customizing stickers from collections which can be free or paid.

Role: IOS single developer.

Languages: Swift. **Duration**: 4 months.

Country of releasing: Australia.

Features: Custom UIViews with gesture recognizers. Core Image framework, Amazon Simple storage service

ASW \$3, In-app purchases.

URL: http://babychalk5.wixsite.com/babychalk

VIVID

Description: IOS and Android application developed for Vivid Cleaning Services Pty Ltd in order to integrate into the company Management System to improve the quality of their services by providing accurate time and positioning when employees enter and leave a site as well as share issues and reports in real time.

Role: IOS developer. Languages: Objective C. Duration: 3 months.

Country of releasing: Australia, Belrose NSW.

Features: Geolocation, Interaction with API and databases, Barcode reading, push notifications.

URL: http://www.vividservices.com.au/

NOQ

Description: This app allows people who attend festivals to order their favourite food and drinks from stalls nearby. It communicates with a remote server and includes content management system and mobile application for IOS and Android devices.

Role: Android single developer.

Languages: Java.

Duration: 4 months.

Country of releasing: Australia, Sidney NSW.

Features: User geographic location, consumes Restful based API service, push notifications, Braintree integration for payment purposes, beautiful design.

Electronic Engineer, Control design ASAHI VISION, **Nagoya**, **Aichi**, **Japan**

04/2015 to 09/2015

http://www.asahi-vision.com/

DEVELOPMENT TEAM: 18 members

DUTIES:

- Control design of Auto alignment mechanism of ophthalmic equipment,
- Development of algorithms.
- Carry on simulations in Matlab.
- Drawing of control flows of multiple mechanisms.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS:

- I had the first experience working in a Japanese culture atmosphere.
- Acquired lots of experience using DRBFM, Design Review Based on Failure Mode as a development management system.
- Learn a lot about machines development and detection of failures.

***** EDUCATION

Bachelor of Applied Science - BASc: Electronic Engineering and telecommunication systems.

INDUSTRIAL UNIVERSITY OF SANTANDER (UIS)

12/2013 Bucaramanga, Colombia.

English and Business THE LONDON SCHOOL OF ENGLISH 10/2011

London, United Kingdom

***** LANGUAGE SKILLS

JAPANESE

Level: Intermediate conversational Business Level. Basic writing. Certificate: JLPT N3. Score: 70/180. December 04, 2016, Nagoya.

ENGLISH

Level: Fluent

Certificate: IELTS. Score: 7.0 / 9.0. April 23, 2012, London.

SPANISH

Native level.